准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
回归自然
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
水母田
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
醒醒  小子
Wake up, boy
你要把我钱烧光了
You're burning me money
蟹老板  怎么办
Mr. Krabs, what do we do?
给  用这个
Here, use this
万岁
Hooray
海绵宝宝  来我办公室一趟
SpongeBob, come into me office
你是怎么了  小子
What's wrong, boy?
那个  我
Well, I
我这周已经是第四次
This is the fourth time this week
把你从烤架上刮下来了
I've had to scrape you off of something
我一直在想别的
Well, I've been thinking
必须要让你多去想工作的事
We need to get you thinking about work
无意冒犯  蟹老板
No offense, Mr. Krabs
我一直在考虑
but I've been thinking
要放弃冷冰冰的工业生活
about giving up my cold industrial life
转而选择更加自然更加自由的生活
in favor of a more natural and free life
栖身于水母之间
among the jellyfish
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你在野外绝对撑不过一天
you wouldn't last even one day in the wild
这是你的自然栖息地
This is your natural habitat
这是你的开阔牧场
This is your wide-open range
这些是你的琥珀色海浪
These are your amber waves
这个
And this
这是由你支配的黄金权杖
This is your golden scepter with which you rule
比你那些恶心的水母强多了
That's better than nasty old jellyfish
对吧  海绵宝宝
Right, SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
我可以撑得过一天的
I can too last more than one day
给他瞧好了
I'll show him
真见鬼
Barnacles
海绵宝宝  等等
SpongeBob, wait
他会回来的  准没错
He'll be back, all right
他会回来的
He'll be back
章鱼哥
And, Squidward
请你收下我的开罐器
I want you to have my can opener
我还以为这份友情没有回报
And I thought this friendship would never pay off
你
Are
你确定要给我这瓶蛋黄酱吗
Are you sure you want to give me this mayonnaise?
全都是你的了
It's all yours
还有这些旧电话簿
And these old phone books?
全都是你的了  老朋友
All yours, old friend
派大星  还有一样东西
Patrick, there is one more thing
我要你收下
I want you to have
可靠好朋友
Ol' reliable?
你好啊
Howdy, y'all
海绵宝宝  你在开跳蚤市场吗
Hey, SpongeBob, you having a garage sale?
没有  珊迪
No, sandy
我要放弃我所有物质财产
I'm giving up my material possessions
去野外跟水母一起生活
to live in the wild with the jellyfish
海绵宝宝  你这什么疯狂计划
SpongeBob, of all the crazy schemes
你怎么会要跟水母一块生活
why would you want to live among the jellyfish?
它们又冷血又坏  没一个聪明的
They're cold and mean and none too bright
珊迪
Sandy
我就想听到你这种回答
that's exactly the response
I would expect from someone
你还活在我过去那种虚假的生活里呢
who lives the sham of a life I once lived
我要证明
I'm gonna prove
想要快乐根本不需要这些玩意
that I don't need all this stuff to be happy
终有一天你们会醒悟  而来加入我
Maybe someday you'll wise up and join me
再见
Good-bye
这个我用不着了
I won't be needing these
他把裤子脱了
He took off his pants
他一周时间回来
I'll give him a week
他十一分钟就回来
I'll give him 11 minutes
派大星好伤心
Patrick sad
水母田
我回家了
I'm home
兄弟姐妹们  等等我
Brothers and sisters, wait for me
好了  我到了
Okay, I'm here
等等  我才刚到呢
Wait, I just got here
我的水母本能告诉我要走
My jellyfish instincts tell me to go
那边
That way
这就是生活
This is the life
各位
Hey, everybody
向你嗡个好
Buzz to you
今天水流不错
Nice current today
今天怎样
What's the buzz?
你好  我是水母宝宝
Hello, I'm JellyBob--
请问你是
And you are?
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you
给  派大星
Here, Patrick
吃个蟹黄堡
Have a Krabby Patty
他来了  派大星
There he is, Patrick
念台词
Say your line
谢谢你  珊迪
"Why, thank you, Sandy
我好想吃
I would love one
拿蟹黄堡
'Take patty'
真可惜海绵宝宝不在
Too bad SpongeBob isn't here
这些可是他的最爱
These are his favorites
真希望他能回家啊
I sure wish he'd come home
咬一口
'Take bite'"
我做不到
I can't do it
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
回来吧
Come back
派大星  我才不回去
Patrick, I'm not coming home
我好想你
I miss you
珊迪好想你
Sandy misses you
连章鱼哥都好想你
Even Squidward misses you
我在这很快乐
I'm happy here
现在这里才是我家
This is my home now
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
各位  我回来了
Hey, everybody, I'm back
我好像快掌握诀窍了
I think I'm getting the hang of this
派大星  你在干什么
Patrick, what are you doing?
要是你不能当我朋友
If I can't have you as a friend
那我就把你当猎物抓走
I'm going to make you a trophy
我甚至还给你挑了个好罐子
I even picked out this nice jar for you
海绵宝宝  朋友
派大星  快回家
Patrick, go home
我现在是水母
I'm a jellyfish now
我看得到你
I can see you there
还是能看得到你
I still see you
把你放我壁炉架上一定很好看
You're going to look good on my mantel
我们永远都是好朋友  海绵宝宝
Friends forever, SpongeBob
我要抓到你了  海绵宝宝
I got you now, SpongeBob
派大星  不要
Patrick, no
行
Okay
看来只能这样了
So this is the way it's going to be
希望你能快乐
I hope you're happy
行了  全都结束了
Well, that's over
继续做水母的事
Back to jellyfish matters
水母酱
Jelly
我的水母同胞要回来了
My jellyfish brethren are returning
你们好  兄弟们
Greetings, comrades
当水母真的好有意思
Being a jellyfish sure is fun
痒死了
I'm itchy
痒
Itchy--
我怎么会这么痒
Why am I so itchy?
有毒的海胆
Poison sea urchins
痒
Itch
裤头村
关
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
珊迪
Sandy
我都干了些什么
What have I done?
我生活好  朋友也好
I had a great life and friends
可我却全都放弃了
and I gave all of that up
欢迎回家  海绵宝宝
Welcome home, SpongeBob
欢迎回家
你们最棒了
You guys are the best
我犯了个天大的错误
I made a huge mistake
请原谅我
Please forgive me
别哭了  吃个蟹黄堡吧
Quit your blubbering and have a Krabby Patty
我这就吃
Don't mind if I do
明早第一件事就是要去上班
And I'll see you at work first thing tomorrow morning
遵命  船长
Aye, aye, captain
海绵宝宝  请你行行好吧
SpongeBob, do us all a favor
我这就穿
Don't mind if I do
这样就行了
Okay, that's enough
能别这样了吗
Could we please stop this?
派大星好痒
Patrick itchy
回家的感觉真好
It is great to be home
相反日
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
生日快乐
惊喜
Surprise
生日快乐  章鱼哥
Happy birthday, Squidward
生日生日快乐
Happy, happy birthday
来吃生日蛋糕
Happy birthday cake
生日生日快乐
Happy, happy birthday
别上海马尾巴
Pin the tail on the sea horse
[ 改自pin the tail on the donkey游戏
蒙眼把驴尾巴钉到无尾驴图片上 ]
生日生日快乐
Happy, happy birthday
生日快乐  章鱼哥
Happy birthday, Squidward
再见  章鱼哥
So long, Squidward
拜拜
Bye-bye
别干我不会去干的傻事
Don't do anything I wouldn't do
又长大了一岁
Another year older
今天不是我生日
It's not my birthday
够了
That's it
我要从这搬出去
I'm moving out of this neighborhood
好的  章鱼哥先生
Absolutely, Mr. Tentacles
我可以马上卖掉你家
I can sell your home in a heartbeat
裤头村房产
真是好消息
That's great news
因为我要尽快搬走
because I want to move as soon as possible
没问题
No problem
只要房子不闹线虫
As long as it's not infested with nematodes
或者旁边没有烦人的邻居
or surrounded by troublesome neighbors
诸如此类的
or something like that
那当然  一个都没有
Sure, there's none of that
你说邻居吗
Did you say neighbors?
当然了
Of course
我都数不清碰见过多少次
I can't tell you how many times
房子被烂邻居害得卖不出去的情况
I've seen a sale fall through because of bad neighbors
邻居
Neighbors
总之  我明天就过去看房
Anyway, I'll be by tomorrow to check out the house
到时候见
See you then
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
有他住隔壁  没人会买我房子的
No one will ever buy my house with him living next door
好邻居该做的事
Whatever a good neighbor would do
他都会按相反的来
he does the opposite
相反
Opposite
章鱼哥
Squidward
你怎么在打鼓
Why are you playing the drum?
鼓
Drum?
什么鼓
What drum?
这只是我的假发盒  看见没
This is just my wig case, see?
快  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
阻截我
Tackle me
章鱼哥  你需要躺床上休息
Squidward, you need bed rest
我会保护你的  直到你康复为止
I'll keep you safe until you're well again
我知道了
I get it
你不知道今天什么日子对吧
You don't know what day it is, do you?
星期三
Wednesday?
今天是相反日
Why, it's opposite day
你是不是从来没听说过
You may you never heard of it?
你是不是都错过了
Boy, have you been missing out
相反日是一年当中
Opposite day is the one day of the year
大家都会反着来的日子
when you get to act different
平常我古板又无趣
Normally I'm stuffy and boring
但今天我呆傻又放肆
but today I'm silly and spontaneous
所有人都知道相反日吗
Does everybody know about opposite day?
当然
Sure
这是游戏  明白吗
It's a game, get it?
游戏
A game
对
Yeah
平常你又吵又讨厌
Normally, you're really loud and annoying
那么今天你要怎么样呢
so what are you going to be today?
安静不烦人
Quiet and out of the way
对
Yeah
你要不就先来一手
Why don't you get a jump on it
我爱
I love
我是说  我恨相反日
I mean, I hate opposite day
我没准备好
I'm not ready
永别了  老朋友
So long, chum
再见了  裤头村
And good-bye, Bikini Bottom
小蜗  今天是相反日
Gary, it's opposite day
我要
and I'm--
走路  不快跑
Walk, don't run
我要
And I'm going to
相反  相反
Opposite, opposite
我要趴到床上
I'm just going to crawl into bed
整天什么都不做
and do nothing all day
真可惜相反日就一年一次  对吧小蜗
Too bad it only comes once a year, huh, Gary?
小蜗  你的节日精神在哪
Gary, where's your holiday spirit?
同伴
Company
我讨厌同伴
I hate company
是谁
Who's there?
是派大星
It's Patrick
派大星
Patrick
滚开
Go away
我再也不想见到你了
I never want to see you again
海绵宝宝再也不喜欢我了
SpongeBob doesn't like me anymore
没错
That's right
你是我的死对头
You're my worst enemy
派大星  你不能算不是我的朋友
Patrick, you're not really not my friend
今天是相反日
It's just opposite day
相反日
Opposite day?
这我听说过
I've heard of that
你听说过
You have?
没有  是什么
No, what is it?
就是平常做什么
Well, whatever you normally do
今天都按相反的来
today you do the opposite
我试试  我试试
Let me try, let me try
派大星
Patrick
派大星  呼吸
Patrick, breathe
相反不是那样的
Not that opposite
我来给你示范
Let me show you how to do it
错误做法
the wrong way
小蜗
星大派
Kcirtap yeh
了服我
Pu evig I
面对路马到要鸡小为因
Edis etisoppo eht ot teg ot
我说  要来帮我在家附近干点活吗
Say, "Want to help me do some work around the house
死对头
worst enemy?"
不要
Nope
快中午了都没看到海绵宝宝
Nearly noon and not a peep from SpongeBob
我几乎都后悔要搬走了
I'm almost sorry I'm leaving
易碎
相反日
Opposite day
海绵宝宝  你在
SpongeBob, what are you?
你好  章鱼哥
Hello, Squidward
我是说
I mean
再见  章鱼哥
Good-bye, Squidward
相反日是不是
Isn't opposite day
很糟糕
Terrible
我来告诉你住你隔壁哪糟糕了
I'll tell you what's terrible living next to you
你就是史上最差的邻居
You're the worst neighbor in history
刚刚那是章鱼哥对我说过最好的话了
That's the nicest thing Squidward has ever said to me
要是房产中介看到那团乱
If the real estate agent sees that mess
我这房子就卖不出去了
I'll never sell this house
是不是很漂亮
Isn't it beautiful?
相反日这天是这样的
On opposite day it is
快让开  海绵宝宝
Out of the way, SpongeBob
我不明白
I don't get it
我把我家弄得一团乱
I made my house a mess
表示的就是清理干净
which was making it clean
导致章鱼哥过来清理我庭院
which made Squidward clean my yard
可那就表示他在弄乱庭院
But that means he's messing it up
但干净的反义词是肮脏
But the opposite of clean is filth
表示脏东西是干净的
which means filth is clean
所以章鱼哥真在给我庭院搞破坏
That means Squidward's really
making my yard a wreck
可平常我庭院都我搞
But I'd normally wreck my own yard
所以章鱼哥现在是章鱼哥的相反
which means Squidward's being
the opposite of Squidward
所以他是海绵宝宝
which means he's SpongeBob
我全都明白了
I understand everything now
我想当海绵宝宝的相反  就要当
I must be the opposite of SpongeBob by being
章鱼哥
Squidward
我也想相反
I want to be opposite, too
总算相反了
Yeah, finally
我是章鱼哥  我是章鱼哥
I'm Squidward, I'm Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
等等
Wait
单是样子像章鱼哥还不够相反
It's not enough to look like Squidward to be opposite
必须要表现得跟他一样
You have to act like him, too
天啊
Boy, oh, boy
我喜欢吹竖笛
Do I like playing the clarinet
我整天都练啊练
I practice and practice all day long
却一点长进也没有
but I never get any better
你来试试
Now you try
好
Okay
我是章鱼哥  章鱼哥
I'm Squidward, Squidward
我是章鱼哥  我是章鱼哥
I'm Squidward, I'm Squidward
我是章鱼哥  章鱼哥
I'm Squidward, Squidward
你先请  章鱼哥先生
After you, Mr. Squidward
好
Fine
谢谢你  章鱼哥先生
Thank you, Mr. Squidward
不用客气  章鱼哥先生
You're quite welcome, Mr. Squidward
相反日
Opposite day
下次怕不是跳崖日
Next time, it's going to be "Go jump off a cliff" day
裤头村房产
天啊
Oh, my
过来看房感觉更漂亮了
The house is even more beautiful in person
你好  章
Hello, Mist
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Tentacles?
是  请进
Yes, please come in
好奇怪
It's funny
我以为你要高得多
I pictured you being much taller
对  大家都这么说
Yeah, everyone says that
想要卖房成功的话
Now if you want the sale to go through
就要先跟我说说房子的优点
you've got to tell me
all the positive things about your house
优点
Positive things--
相反日
Opposite day
可以
I'd love to
地板会响  屋顶漏水
The floor creaks, the roof leaks
穿堂风很严重
There's a terrible draft
你电话里都没说啊
Well, you didn't mention that on the phone
让我先说完
Please let me finish
冬天很难熬
The winters are hard
夏天又毒辣
The summers are brutal
后院里头还有只吃人的野蛤蜊
There's a wild man-eating clam in the backyard
想看看我家其他地方吗
Would you care to see the rest of my home?
那个  我不太确定我有没有兴趣
Well, I'm not sure if I'm interested
荒唐
Nonsense
我不接受否定的回答
I won't take no for an answer
请跟我来
Please follow me
这是我家最烂的房间  我的画廊
And here's the worst room in the house, my gallery
天啊  这些画真好看
Oh, my, this painting is very nice
谢谢
Thank you
那是谁
Who's that?
我要向你介绍章鱼哥先生
I'd like to introduce you to Mr. Squidward
你们俩都是章鱼哥
You're both Squidward?
我是章鱼哥
I'm Squidward
他是章鱼哥
He's Squidward
我们都是章鱼哥
We're both Squidward
整完了
Well, that's done
起码海绵宝宝一直都很安静
At least SpongeBob has been quiet
裤头村房产
不
No
好了  我真的不想再听一首了
Okay, I really don't want to hear another one
好
Okay
我真的不想再听了  谢谢
I really don't want to hear more, thank you
我听得很清楚
I hear you loud and clear
住手
Stop
离她远一点
Get away from her
真对不起  女士
I am so sorry, ma'am
希望这两个白痴
I hope these two barnacle-heads
没伤到你
haven't harmed you in any way
你是谁
Who are you?
好
Fine
我是章鱼哥
I'm Squidward
你是把我当成什么傻子了
What kind of fool do you take me for?
他是章鱼哥
He's Squidward?
你是章鱼哥
You're Squidward?
我是章鱼哥
I'm Squidward
还有没有别的章鱼哥我该认识的
Are there any other Squidwards I should know about?
我这就走
I'm out of here
女士  求你了
Ma'am, please
我房子怎么办
What about my house?
就算只剩你一个章鱼哥
I wouldn't sell a house for you
我也不会帮你卖房子的
if you were the last Squidward on Earth
等等
Wait
别
Don't
走
Go
不不不
No, no, no
求你卖我房子吧
Please sell my house
免谈
Never
你别走啊
Don't leave me here
相反日快乐  章鱼哥
Happy opposite day, Squidward
我们讨厌你
We hate you
我来给你们瞧瞧
Let me show you guys
我有多讨厌你们
how much I hate you
派大星  你有没有觉得
Patrick, you ever feel
章鱼哥太喜欢我们了
that Squidward likes us too much?
相反日快乐
Happy opposite day